No! Not that!
駄目だよ
それは駄目だよ
Do it!
やっちゃえ
Wait! Let's not be hasty here!
待て
早まるな
Yoru o oou mabuta hirake
夜ヲ覆ウ目蓋開ケ
Waruki kage o osoreru nakare
凶キ影ヲ恐レルナカレ
Honoguraki hitsugi kara
仄くらき柩から
Umiotosareta ningyou no you ni
産み堕とされた人形のように
Karada wa akaku kogoe
躰は赤く凍え
Kokoro wa yami ni ayasare sodatsu
心は闇にあやされ育つ
Kimi ni boku ga mieru kai
君に僕が見えるかい
Tsunagu te no tsumetasa ni
つなぐ手の冷たさに
Senketsu no tsume tateru
鮮血の爪立てる
Mayu yosete goran yo
眉寄せてごらんよ
壊し合おう先に続く 謎に満ちる結末を
Kowashiaou saki ni tsuzuku
Nazo ni michiru ketsumatsu o
Hane mo ashi mo mogareta mama
羽も脚ももがれたまま
Kokuu no naka kuchihateru yori
虚空のなか朽ち果てるより
Mou hitori boku ga ite
もうひとり僕がいて
Dareka o itai hodo aishite irun da
誰かを痛いほど愛しているんだ
Saa docchi ga maboroshi darou ne
さぁどっちが幻だろうね
All right!
よし
He stopped it?
止めた
He said he stopped the calamity
fifteen years ago?
十五年前の災厄を止めたって言うの
That's what he claims,
そういうことを本人が言ったらしくて
though he apparently doesn't
remember any details.
ただ 詳しいこと覚えていないらしいんです
Do you remember Mr. Matsunaga?
怜子さんは松永さんのこと 覚えてますか
Of course, we were in the same club.
もちろん
同じ部活だったしね
You were?
そうだったんですか
Did he ever talk about how he stopped it?
その どうやって止めたとか
そういう話 何か聞いてませんか
I can't recall ever hearing anything about that.
そんなこと一言も
何も聞いてないと思う
You went on a class trip during
summer break that year, right?
十五年前の夏休みって 合宿があったんですよね
Yes.
そう
It didn't seem like a good idea
to stay confined at home.
あの夏じっと家に閉じこもってるのはよくないんじゃないかと思って
その合宿で何が
What happened on that trip?
I'm sure something happened,
何かあったのは確かだと思うんだけど
but I couldn't tell you what.
じゃ なんだったのかって言われても
I see...
そうですか
I'm no help, I know.
不甲斐ないわね
Sorry.
ごめんなさい
It's okay.
そんな
I'm fine,
僕は大丈夫ですから
so there's no need to push yourself.
だから怜子さんもあまり無理をしないでくださいね
So, Mr. Matsunaga went on the trip too?
じゃあ その合宿に松永さんは来てました
I think so.
行ったはず
Yeah, he did.
うん 来てた
Did anything seem strange about him?
何か変わった様子はありませんでした
I don't think so.
特に無かったと 思う
I guess all we can do is ask him.
やっぱ本人に聞くしかないか
Okay, I'll run it by Matsu for you.
分かった
松には私が話をつけるね
When you go to talk to him, I'll go with you.
話を聞く時は私も行くから
Morning!
おはようっす
Good morning!
おはようございます
Morning.
おはよう
What's all that stuff for?
何その荷物
I stocked up on supplies!
色々準備してきたからな
Sorry to keep you.
お待たせ
Are you okay?
大丈夫
You don't look so good.
顔色良くない
It's nothing.
どうってことねえ
Just a little carsi...
ちょっと車に酔う
He tries too hard.
無理しやがって
You're coming too, Akazawa?
赤沢さんも行くの
Of course I am.
当たり前でしょう
Why don't you ride in this car?
恒一くんこっちの車に乗らない
Yours doesn't look like it can handle four.
その車で四人はきついんじゃない
It's no problem.
そんなことないよ
This car runs better than you'd think.
意外とよく走るよ
That was unnecessary.
「意外」は余計です
Okay...
そう
Then, Teshigawara, you're in my car.
じゃ 勅使河原 私の車ね
Um, okay.
Nakao, since you get carsick, you're up front.
中尾は車に酔うから 前ね
Okay...
はい
Well, let's go.
じゃ 行きましょうか
So, Mr. Matsunaga won't be coming back
to Yomiyama for a while?
その松永さんって人は 暫く夜見山には戻って来ないんですか
I spoke to his mother
彼のお母さんに聞いたんだけどね
and she said he's living at the
resort hotel where he works.
あっちのリゾートホテルに住み込みで働いてるみたい
City of Yomiyama
Please Come Again!
Sanami Town
We made it out of Yomiyama
without any trouble.
無事に夜見山を出られたみたいね
Yeah...
そっか
Let's get a move on!
さーて 行きますか
Um, Reiko?
あの 怜子さん
What?
何
Oh, nothing...
いいえ なんでもないです
Damn it, if you're gonna drive that slow,
get out of the fast lane.
ったく 尋だら右走しんないんだよね
I guess you can't judge a book by its cover.
人は見かけによらずって感じね
I don't know, I think you're pretty easy to read.
赤沢さんは見かけどおりって感じだけど
Oh, yeah?
Please, describe me.
私ってどういう感じなの
Uh, well...
えっ そうだな
Strong and dependable?
強くたくましい
Wow, am I that macho?
うわ 私 そんなにマッチョ
Well, you are tough,
押しが強いとことか 責任感が強いとことか
and you've got a strong sense
of responsibility.
Stuff like that.
色々ね
You're supposed to say,
"That's not what I meant."
「そんなこと無いよ」ぐらい言いなさいよ
That's not what I meant.
そんなこと無いよ
What's with the tone? So annoying.
何それ むかつく
I've gotta pay you back now and then.
たまには仕返ししないとね
そういや 赤沢さんって対策係なんだよね
By the way, you're the head of
countermeasures, right?
How is it decided who gets that role?
それって どうやって決まるものなの
Usually, they're appointed by the teacher.
普通は先生のご指名ね
It's not a popular job.
誰もやりたくないと思うし
In a way,
言ってみれば クラスの皆の命を預かるわけでしょう
you could say they're responsible
for the lives of the entire class.
So, were you appointed?
じゃあ 赤沢さんも
I nominated myself.
私は立候補
Why?
どうして
Maybe no one else actually
believed in the calamity,
他の人は災厄なんて信じていなかったでしょうけどね
but I was different.
私は違う
I can't allow such a senseless
phenomenon to exist.
私は許さない 理不尽なこの現象を
I'm going to put an end to it.
だから 私が止めるの
So hot...
あちー
They said Matsunaga was
suddenly called to a reception.
松永くん急な出迎えに出てるらしくて
I left my cell phone number,
一応私の携帯の番号を教えたから
so he should call me when he gets back.
戻って来たら連絡が来るはずだけど
What should we do until then?
それまでどうしよう
No point in sitting around waiting, right?
ただ待っててもしょうがねえよな
Yeah, we came all this way.
だよね ここまで来たんだし
Since we're outside Yomiyama,
the calamity shouldn't affect us.
ここは夜見山の外だし 災厄も及ばないはずよ
Yes! Then, let's go swimming!
よし じゃあ 泳ぐか
We are near the ocean after all.
せっかく海に来たんだしね
All right!
やりい
But I didn't bring my trunks!
僕 水着なんて持って来て無いですよ
You can get some at the hotel.
水着ならホテルで買えると思うよ
They don't cost much.
そんなに高いもんじゃないし
I'll buy you a pair.
買ってあげるよ
I couldn't ask you to do that.
え そんな 悪いですよ
If you're not swimming, I won't either.
怜子さんが泳がないなら 僕も
Well, I thought this might happen, so...
私は その こんなこともあろうかと
Oh, don't tell me...
え まさか
I thought that seemed like a lot of luggage.
荷物が多いと思ったら
It's a seaside resort after all.
せっかくの海だし
Not to mention we're outside Yomiyama.
なんと言っても夜見山の外だしね
And it's summer break.
夏休みなんだし
It would be too depressing to sit
at home the entire time.
部屋にこもってても気がめいるだけでしょう
We have to spread our wings a little.
少しは羽伸ばさないと
It's the sea!
海だ
The sea in summer!
夏の海
It's mine!
俺の海
All right!
そうりゃー やっほー
Misaki?
見崎
Sakakibara?
榊原 くん
そーれ
Heave-ho!
Oh no, my glasses...
あ 眼鏡 眼鏡
You'll pay for that!
よくもやったな
行くぞ つい
Ready, set, dunk!
Is your family's summer house nearby?
あのさ 見崎ちの別荘ってこの近くなの
Yes.
そう
What does your dad do?
見崎のお父さんって何してる人
I'm not quite sure.
詳しくは知らない
He's rarely in Japan.
ほとんど日本にいないから
That's why we put on these little family acts
on the rare occasions when he comes home.
だから
たまに帰って来てはこうやって家族サービスの真似事
We may be a family,
but we aren't really connected.
家族とは言っても
ほとんど繋がっていない感じ
Not that I care.
別にいいけど
Hey, if we find out who the
dead person is after this,
あのさ もしこの後 死者の正体が分かったらさ
would making them nonexistent
stop the calamity?
そいつを「いないもの」にしてしまえば 災厄は止まるかな
I don't think that would work.
それはきっと駄目だと思う
It's already been triggered.
もう始まってしまってるから
I think it's too late to try to balance
everything out now.
いまから帳尻を合わそうとしても 遅いと思う
Did they connect?
繋がったかな
Seems so.
たぶん
Connecting every now and then
can't be so bad, can it?
たまには 繋がってもいいんじゃないかな
たまには ね
I suppose.
Anyone up for lunch?
そろそろお昼にしましょうか
はい
Yes!
Hey, wait!
待ってよ
Should we go back to the hotel?
ホテルに戻ります
I'm fine with something from
a convenience store.
コンビニとかでもいいけど
There are also seaside shops.
「海の家」という手もありますね
Hold it, you guys!
待て 待て お前ら
We're at the beach.
せっかく海に来たんだ
How could we not make the most
of the outdoor life?
アウトドアライフを満喫せんでどうする
You want to cook here?
ここで料理でもするの
I knew you'd get it, Akazawa!
さすが赤沢
分かってんな
What?
はあ 道具もなしにどうすんのよ
How are we supposed to do
that without any tools?
I've got the bases covered!
抜かりはないわ
Take a look at this flawless setup!
見よ この完璧な装備
You're such an idiot.
バカでしょ あんた
This is what was in that huge bag?
あの大荷物はこれだったんだ
Are you going to cook?
料理するの
Huh? Cook?
えっ 料理
With what ingredients?
食材は
Local fare, of course!
現地調達に決まってんだろう
Definitely an idiot.
バカでしょ あんた
With all the stuff you brought,
I should have known...
ここまで来るとは さすがだな
I'm hungry.
お腹空いた
Local fare?
調達
Mochizuki!
望月
You brought the fishing gear, right?
釣り道具を持ってきてるよな
Oh, yeah!
All right, then let's see who can
round up the most ingredients!
よし
食材調達勝負と行こうぜ
Do we get anything for winning or losing?
勝ち負けで何かあるわけ
The loser has to make the food,
負けた方は料理を作る
and the winner gets to eat it.
勝った方は料理を食う
How's that?
どうよ
Sounds interesting.
面白そうじゃない
Then it's settled!
決まりだな
I'll pick the teams.
じゃ チーム分け
First off, on the Head of
Countermeasures Team will be...
まずは 対策係チーム
Akazawa!
赤沢 杉浦 中…
Sugiura!
Naka...
Actually, we'll pass on him.
こいつはパス
And me!
んで 俺
Now, on the Nonexistent Team will be...
お次は 「いないもの」チーム
Sakakibara!
榊原 見崎 望月
Misaki!
Mochizuki!
Hey, I exist!
僕 「いないもの」じゃ
But you don't exist over here.
いや お前ここにいないし
Harsh...
ひどい
So we're competing based on
the fish we catch?
釣った魚で勝負するの
No, if you find anything besides fish,
it counts too.
いや 魚いないでも何かありゃあ それも
Let me out!
出してよ
That's sea lettuce.
それはあおさ
美味しくないよ
It tastes awful.
That's red algae.
それはてんぐさ
You can't eat it on its own.
そのままじゃ無理だね
I got one!
来た こいつはでけえぞ
It's a big one!
Yes!
やった
What is this?
なに これ
Kelp.
昆布
You're supposed to catch fish!
魚釣りなさいよ
Sorry.
すみません
What's wrong?
どうした
Get it off...
取って
食べられるかと思った
I thought it was going to eat me.
Octopuses don't eat people.
たこは人を食べないよ
They'll bite if you poke at them, though.
突き回すとも 噛まれるけどね
How's it going?
どう
I think I've got a big one...
大物 かも
It's pulling pretty hard.
かなり引きが強い
All right!
やった
That's your big one?
大物
At least it's a fish.
一応魚だよ
Cute.
可愛い
I've got one this time!
来た
今度こそ
Hey...
ちょっと
You're doing that on purpose, aren't y...
あんた絶対狙ってるでしょ
何これ
What is this?!
なまこ
A sea cucumber?
I'm actually impressed you
caught one of these.
っていうか なまこ釣るって 凄いな
ひっかけただけか
Or maybe it just got caught on the line.
このぺけ子 役立たず
You creep! Useless jerk!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
すみません すみません
A pufferfish, an octopus and a starfish.
ふぐ たこにひとで
This is kelp, right?
昆布よね これ
And a sea cucumber and...
なまこと
What's in this shell?
この巻き貝は
A hermit crab.
ヤドカリ
I guess that's how it goes.
ま こんなものよね
This battle ends in a draw.
この勝負 引き分け
I picked up some meat and vegetables,
so let's all eat that.
お肉と野菜を買ってきておいたから
皆で食べましょうね
Okay!
はい
ヤッパ取り立てはうめえな
Freshly-caught really is the best!
Oh, how I love that crunch.
この歯ごたえ 美味しい
So delicious!
We definitely can't eat these guys.
さすがにそいつは食えないかな
Got it!
ほれー
Reiko?
怜子か
I tried calling your cell.
携帯に電話したんだけどな
Is the battery dead?
電池切れてないか
Huh?
え ありゃあ
Oops...
Careless as ever, I see.
相変わらず そそっかしいんだな
I'm surprised you found us here.
よくここが分かったわね
Wasn't hard to figure out.
分かったも何も ホテルに一番近い浜だからな ここは
This is the closest beach to the hotel.
Ah...
そっか
But, wow...
うん しかし 女は化けるもんだな
Girls sure do change.
You used to be a shrimp.
あんなチンチクリンの小娘がな
You've changed quite a bit, yourself.
そういう松も ずいぶん変わったんじゃない
Into an old geezer.
すっかりおじさん
Shut up!
Into an old geezer.
うっせえよ
It's been fifteen years, huh?
十五年ぶり か
Technically, it's only been fourteen years
since our graduation.
卒業式以来だから まだ十四年じゃない
Oh, yeah.
そうか
That makes us around thirty, huh?
十五年ぶりだと 三十歳だもんな
Don't remind me.
うるさいよ
Wait...
Have I seen you somewhere recently?
もっと最近 会ってなかったか
Where?
どこで
I don't remember seeing you.
私は覚えてないけど
It was probably a different girl.
それ 別の女の子じゃない
Unfortunately, I don't think it was.
残念ながら それはない
Then, maybe it was at Kentarou or
Natsuko's memorial services?
じゃあ ケンタロウかナツコの法要とかで
No, I only went to the funerals.
いや 俺は葬式しか出てないから
Oh...
そう
Can't believe it's been fifteen years
since they died.
あいつらが死んでもう十五年か
Who are the kids?
あの子らは
This year's Class 3 students.
今年の三年三組の生徒
Oh...
そうか
They're here about what happened
fifteen years ago?
十五年前のこと か
I can only remember bits and pieces
of that summer, myself.
私も あの夏のことは断片的にしか思い出せないの
Matsu, I heard that you stopped the calamity.
松 あなたが「災厄」を止めたって聞いたんだけど
Tomoka at Inoya asked me about that too,
イノヤの智香ちゃんもあんなこと言ってたかな
but I don't remember.
当の本人が覚えてねんだ
Do you recall the class trip
we took that summer?
あの夏の合宿のこと 覚えてる
Yeah...
An accident happened on that trip, right?
合宿中に事故が起きてますよね
Do you remember anything about it?
そのことは覚えておられますか
And you are?
君は
Izumi Akazawa, the head of countermeasures.
対策係の赤沢です
I see.
そうか
To tell you the truth, I don't remember much.
正直 ちゃんと覚えてないんだよ
I know someone died on the mountain, but...
誰かが山に死んだってのは 覚えてるんだが
My memory's hazy, too.
私も覚えてない
I don't know what kind of accident it was.
どんな事故があったのか
Did the accident happen before you
visited the shrine, or after?
あの その事故って 神社のお参りの前ですか 後ですか
Why does that matter?
どういうこと
Well, if it was before,
えっと お参りの前なら
maybe a blessing from the shrine
stopped the calamity.
お参りのご利益で止まったのかもしれないって
I can't recall.
覚えてない
But something tells me it was a run-down,
abandoned-Iooking shrine.
ただ ぼろぼろで見捨てられたような神社に行ったような気がする
Right, the shrine.
そう 神社
I'm sure we went to the shrine.
神社には行ったと思う
We all joined hands and...
皆で手を合わせて
Nope, I just can't remember.
だめ うまく思い出せない
Um, Mr. Matsunaga,
あの
松永さんは 伝えなきゃと思って
didn't you leave something behind,
as a clue for the others?
何かを残したんですよね
Apparently, I said that, but...
俺がそう言ったらしいんだが
What did you want to tell them?
何を伝えようと思ったんですか
All I know is that I felt this
urgent need to tell them, but...
そういう強い気持ちがあったというのは 覚えてるんだけど
You can't remember what about?
でも 思い出せない
And you don't remember what
you left behind, or where?
何をどこに残したか 覚えてないですか
Like if it was a note, or something else?
その メモのようなものとか
No, it wasn't paper...
ああ 紙じゃない 何だ
It was...
What?
何ですか
Yeah, I think I used something...
そう 何かを使ったような
Oh, I know! It's at the school!
そうだ 学校だ
I took something to the school!
学校に何かを持って行ったんだ
The school?
学校って 学校のどこにですか
Where in the school?
I'll get it!
任せろ
How far out are you gonna go?
どこまで行く気だ
What is he doing?
何やってた
This doesn't look good.
まずくない
The hell...
なんだよ
Dude, quit messing around!
しょうもねえことすんなよな
Aw, hell!
ヤベ
Why...
どうして
But I...
俺が 俺が守ったのに
I protected them.
I left it for them...
俺が残したのに
in the classroom.
教室に
Iro aseteku firumu no you ni
色褪せてく フィルムのように
Tashika na ima mo izure kasunde
確かな今も いずれ霞んで
Nan de mo naku waraiatta
何でもなく 笑いあった
Setsuna no jikan to hikari
刹那の時間と光
Tsunagatte yuku kioku no soko ni
繋がってゆく 記憶の底に
Dareka ga mitsukeru tame aru to
誰かが見つけるためあると信じてる 今でも
Shinjiteru ima de mo
"Body paint"